have you ever talked with a friend about a problem
你有没有和朋友谈过一个问题
only to realize that he just doesn't seem to
才意识到他似乎
grasp why the issue is so important to you
理解为什么这个问题对你如此重要
have you ever presented an idea to a group
你有没有向一个小组提出过一个想法？
and it's met with utter confusion
它遇到了完全的混乱
or maybe you've been in an argument when the
或者也许你一直在争论
other person suddenly accuses you of not
另一个人突然指责你没有
listening to what they're saying at all
听听他们在说什么
what's going on here
这是怎么回事？
the answer is miscommunication
答案是沟通不畅
and in some form or another
以某种形式
we've all experienced it
我们都经历过
it can lead to confusion  animosity
它会导致混乱敌意
misunderstanding
误解
or even crashing a multi million
甚至撞坏几百万
dollar probe into the surface of Mars
美元探测火星表面
the fact is
事实是
even when face to face with another person in the
即使在与另一个人面对面的时候
very same room and speaking the same language
同一个房间，说同样的语言
human communication is incredibly complex
人类的交流非常复杂
but the good news is that a basic
但好消息是基本的
understanding of what happens when we
理解当我们
communicate can help us prevent miscommunication
沟通可以帮助我们防止沟通不畅
for decades
几十年来
researchers have asked what
研究人员问
happens when we communicate
发生在我们交流的时候
one interpretation called the transmission
一种解释称为传输
model views communication as a message that
模型将沟通视为一种信息
moves directly from one person to another
直接从一个人转移到另一个人
similar to someone tossing a ball and walking away
类似于有人扔球走人
but in reality
但实际上
this simplistic model doesn't account
这个简单的模型没有考虑到
for communication's complexity
对于通信的复杂性
enter the transactional model
进入交易模型
which acknowledges the many added
这承认了许多添加
challenges of communicating
沟通挑战
with this model
有了这个模型
it's more accurate to think of
想起来更准确
communication between people as a game of catch
人与人之间的交流是一种接球游戏
as we communicate our message
当我们传达我们的信息时
we receive feedback from the other party
我们收到对方的反馈
through the transaction
通过交易
we create meaning together
我们一起创造意义
but from this exchange
但从这次交流中
further complications arise
进一步的并发症出现
it's not like the Star Trek universe where
这不像《星际迷航》中的宇宙
some characters can Vulcan mind meld
有些角色可以瓦肯精神融合
fully sharing thoughts and feelings  as humans
作为人类充分分享思想和感受
we can't help but send and receive
我们不能不发送和接收
messages through our own subjective lenses
通过我们自己的主观镜头传达的信息
when communicating
交流时
one person expresses her interpretation of a message
一个人表达她对信息的解释
and the person she's communicating with hears
和她交流的人听到了
his own interpretation of that message
他自己对该信息的解释
our perceptual filters continually
我们的感知过滤器不断
shift meanings and interpretations
转移含义和解释
remember that game of catch
还记得那个接球游戏吗
imagine it with a lump of clay
用一块粘土来想象它
as each person touches it
当每个人触摸它时
they shape it to fit their own unique
他们把它塑造成适合自己独特的
perceptions based on any number of
基于任意数量的感知
variables like knowledge or past experience  age  race
知识或过去经验年龄种族等变量
gender  ethnicity
性别种族
religion or family background
宗教或家庭背景
simultaneously
同时
every person interprets the message they receive
每个人都会解释他们收到的信息
based on their relationship with the other person
基于他们与对方的关系
and their unique understanding of the semantics and
以及他们对语义学的独特理解
connotations of the exact words being used
所使用的确切词语的含义
they could also be distracted by other stimuli
他们也可能被其他刺激分散注意力
such as traffic or a growling stomach
比如堵车或者肚子咕咕叫
even emotion might cloud their understanding
甚至情感也会影响他们的理解
and by adding more people into a conversation
并通过在对话中添加更多人
each with their own subjectivities
每个人都有自己的主观性
the complexity of communication grows exponentially
沟通的复杂性呈指数级增长
so as the lump of clay goes back and
所以当粘土块回去的时候
forth from one person to another  reworked  reshaped
从一个人到另一个人重新加工重塑
and always changing
并且总是在变化
it's no wonder our messages sometimes
难怪我们的信息有时
turn into a mush of miscommunication
变成一堆沟通不畅
but luckily
但幸运的是
there are some simple practices that
有一些简单的做法
can help us all navigate our daily
可以帮助我们所有人导航我们的日常生活
interactions for better communication
互动以实现更好的沟通
1  recognize that passive hearing and
1认识到被动听觉和
active listening are not the same
主动倾听不一样
engage actively with the verbal and
积极参与口头和
nonverbal feedback of others
他人的非语言反馈
and adjust your message to
并将您的消息调整为
facilitate greater understanding
增进了解
2  listen with your eyes and ears
2用眼睛和耳朵听
as well as with your gut
以及你的直觉
remember that communication is more than just words
记住沟通不仅仅是言语
3  take time to understand
3花时间去理解
as you try to be understood
当你试图被理解时
in the rush to express ourselves
急于表达自己
it's easy to forget that
很容易忘记这一点
communication is a two way street
沟通是双向的
be open to what the other person might say
对对方可能说的话持开放态度
and finally  4
最后是4
be aware of your personal perceptual filters
注意您的个人感知过滤器
elements of your experience
你的经验要素
including your culture
包括你们的文化
community and family
社区和家庭
influence how you see the world  say
影响你如何看待世界说
this is how I see the problem
这就是我对问题的看法
but how do you see it
但是你怎么看呢？
don't assume that your
不要假设你的
perception is the objective truth
感知是客观真理
that'll help you work towards sharing a dialogue with
这将有助于您努力与
others to reach a common understanding together
其他人一起达成共识